OPERATIONS MANAGER

Profile

Throughout my career, I have obtained and developed the knowledge, skills, abilities and confidence in a fast paced and efficient work environment. This has enabled me with the opportunity to inspire and develop others. I have obtained this through consistent and ongoing practice of my individual communication skills and the emotional intelligence of myself, my peers, and my subordinates. By combining these key attributes, I am successful and confident in challenges I face. I will continue to succeed progress and develop those I work with in their individual professional and personal endeavors.

Areas of Expertise

- Background in [engineering focus]
- Team player
- Scheduling tools
- Operations research
- Process improvement
- · Quality control

Professional Experience

Operations Manager

June 2014 to Current Gates Corp i1/4 Siloam Springs, AR

- DHL eCommerce) 6670 Business Pkwy, Elkridge MD 21075 U.S.A.
- Performed the major functions of the terminal; supporting the ongoing development and implementation of the DHL eCommerce business plan through timely and accurate mailings while maintaining a cost effective operation.
- Manage production, employees, quality process and transportation in accordance with DHL's policies and procedures to obtain optimal profitability. Ensure a high level of staff morale and high retention rate. Communicate through implementation of a communication plan to include regular formal and informal meetings Recommend measures to improve production methods, working conditions, and increased efficiencies Facilitate human resource management within the facility to include, but not limited to employee relations, recruiting, hiring, and training Implement new standard operating procedures and train employees as needed Handle special projects and project management Monitor and ensure that all facility equipment is working correctly and meeting production standards Act as liaison between the facility and the on-site postal clerks Keep updated on all postal rate/regulatory changes Oversee safety activities to include ensuring compliance with DHL's safety policy, employee training, reporting, and maintaining OSHA logs.

Shift Supervisor

May 2008 to June 2014 Allied Universal Security i1/4 Harrisburg, PA

- DHLGLOBALMAIL) 6670 Business Pkwy, Elkridge MD 21075 U.S.A.
- 7 years work experience.
- Supervised the operations of the encoding and receiving department that they follow all the procedures, policies, safety and quality at all times
- Managed the internal and external quality controls, employee relations, profitability, and volume trending.
- Conducted and ensure employee performance evaluations are completed in a timely and effective manner.
- Coached, trained and developed coworkers and subordinates.
- Work directly with Human Resources including the payroll, staffing, evaluations, employee relations and employee development.
- Developed and maintained best operational practices.
- Managed operational cost, overtime and overall productivity.
- Implemented the process and procedures in receiving and encoding the mail, manifesting and up to shipping.
- Developed a systematic spreadsheet calculation of the daily encoder's efficiency and the calculation of the department cost per unit and the
 pieces per hour.
- Maintained the 100% encoding efficiency with the good quality as per the customer's requirement.

Cost Estimator and Product Coordinator

January 2003 to February 2004 Career Advantage i1/4 Springfield, TN

- Collaborated with the engineers and project managers regarding designs and bill of materials for customer projects.
- Prepared accurate specifications for purchase of materials.
- Reviewed and processed final product specifications for production release.
- Conducted meeting with the Inventory Control analyst and production supervisor to ensure in meeting production lead time and delivery time.

PRODUCTION MANAGER /EXPORT MARKETING MANAGER

June 1994 to January 2003 MARUICHI EXPORT CORP i1/4 City, STATE

- Ensures that export products are produced efficiently; that they are of the right quality, quantity and cost, and that they are produced on time to the satisfaction of the Customer at the right price.
- Personally checked the material resources needed from different places locally and overseas.
- Drafting a timescale and cost implications of the new developing product.
- Calculated the costs of each product and sets the standard quality and the processing instructions.
- Personally interacted heavily with the international customers, over the phone and via email.

Production Planner

June 1990 to May 1994 METROPLAS PACKAGING CORP i1/4 City, STATE

- PHILIPPINES 3 years work experience.
- Analyzed the inventory of the Raw Materials, In Process and Finished products of the plastic bottles and caps.
- Evaluated the daily machines production output and the machine performance.
- Developed the spreadsheets of the Master Plan for the Machines Schedule and its Machine Performance Analysis of the 12 blow mold machines and the 8 injection machines.
- Ensures all parties are fully cognizant of production status and that work planning and execution objectives are integrated and communicated.
- Expedited operations that delay schedules and alters schedules to meet unforeseen conditions.

Education

Thesis in Online Banking (Philippines National Bank) Pharmacy Technician: 2009 Ashworth Career School

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering, 2000 Polytechnic University of the Philippines Microcad Technologies Co. Inc. Philippines it/4 City, Philippines

Accomplishments

 Leadership, Quality Management, Planning and Analysis, Negotiations and Salesmanship, Problem Solving, Staff Development, Quality Assurance, Decision Analysis, Production Planning, Cost Management, Operations Management.

Product Improvement

- Improved overall product performance.
- Eliminated machine defects through recommendation of machine adjustments.

Statistical Analysis

Performed data collection and statistical analysis that resulted in sound recommendations that were adopted by department.

Quality Control

• Saved 8% on supply costs by working closely with suppliers to ensure components met department quality standards.

Testing, Evaluation and Analysis: Â

- Tested equipment to ensure compliance.
- Analyzed data and provided recommendations which resulted in adoption of new cost-saving equipment.

Skills

Banking, business plan, Coach, Drafting, eCommerce, email, employee relations, hiring, human resource, Human Resources, inventory, Materials, meetings, mail, payroll, Performance Analysis, policies, project management, quality, receiving, recruiting, reporting, requirement, safety, shipping, spreadsheets, spreadsheet, staffing, Technician, phone, employee development, employee training, transportation